<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Big Data Storage on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/track/big-data-storage/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Big Data Storage on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/track/big-data-storage/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache Iceberg Planning Explained</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-iceberg-planning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-iceberg-planning-explained/</guid>
      <description>A critical aspect of any table format is the rapid identification of files relevant for a query irrespective of the underlying data volume. The focus of this presentation is on the job planning process in Apache Iceberg, highlighting its efficiency and ability to scale to tens of millions of files. This session will explain how the project leverages a hybrid strategy for planning jobs, seamlessly transitioning between local and distributed execution for optimal performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Ratis - A High Performance Raft Library</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-ratis-a-high-performance-raft-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-ratis-a-high-performance-raft-library/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ratis is an open source Java library for the Raft Consensus Protocol. Raft is being used successfully as an alternative to Paxos to implement a consistently replicated log. Raft is proven to be safe and is designed to be simpler to understand. Ratis is a high performance implementation of Raft. Apache Ozone, Apache IoTDB and Alluxio use Apache Ratis for providing high availability and replicating raw data.
Ratis implements all the standard Raft features, including leader election, log replication, membership change and log compaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevating Scalable Object Storage: A Comprehensive Exploration of Ozone’s Trailblazing Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/elevating-scalable-object-storage-a-comprehensive-exploration-of-ozones-trailblazing-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/elevating-scalable-object-storage-a-comprehensive-exploration-of-ozones-trailblazing-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In the era of explosive data growth, scalability is paramount for any storage solution. This abstract focuses on the scalability aspects of Apache Ozone, a distributed object storage system designed to handle the ever-increasing demands of modern data-intensive applications.
The session will commence with an up-to-date overview of Apache Ozone, providing insights into its current state, recent enhancements, and its pivotal role in addressing the evolving needs of organizations. Attendees will gain a comprehensive understanding of how Apache Ozone offers scalable, high-performance, and future-ready solutions tailored to the challenges posed by today&amp;rsquo;s data-intensive applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Tenancy — Apache Hbase</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/multi-tenancy-apache-hbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/multi-tenancy-apache-hbase/</guid>
      <description>Apache HBase is an open-source non-relational distributed database with multiple components such as Zookeeper, JournalNodes, Hmaster, Namenodes, Datanodes, Regionserver. Managing independent clusters for each use case is operationally heavy and sub-optimal utilization of hardware. Hence there is a need for providing a consolidated, managed, multi-tenant HBase cluster with stronger isolation guarantees in many organizations.
In this talk, we are going to talk about how we approached this problem, made tradeoffs and run large scale multi-tenant hbase clusters with strict isolation guarantees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Impala not only reads, but modifies and optimizes Iceberg tables</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/this-impala-not-only-reads-but-modifies-and-optimizes-iceberg-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/this-impala-not-only-reads-but-modifies-and-optimizes-iceberg-tables/</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a distributed, massively parallel query engine for big data. Initially, it focused on fast query execution on top of large datasets that were ingested via long-running batch jobs. The table schema and the ingested data typically remained unchanged, and row-level modifications were impractical to say the least.
Today&amp;rsquo;s expectations for modern data warehouse engines have risen significantly. Users now want to have RDBMS-like capabilities in their data warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitefox: simple table format sharing</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the evolving landscape of data platforms, the decoupling of compute and storage has led to the emergence of open data systems free from vendor constraints. However, this shift towards &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;modularity&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; brings its own set of challenges. The intricate task of establishing effective access controls within table-format architectures proves to be complex. Despite data residing in the cloud and theoretically accessible from anywhere, the existing friction impedes seamless accessibility.
Enter Whitefox: an open-source initiative inspired by the brilliant principles of Delta-Sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
