<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/track/community/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/track/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Allyship - We need you to power up Diversity</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/allyship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/allyship/</guid>
      <description>Open-source technologies play a significant role in driving technological advancements, fostering collaboration, and encouraging innovation. The Apache Software Foundation is a prominent nonprofit organization in this realm. Nevertheless, unlocking the full potential of these projects necessitates a commitment to embracing diversity and inclusion.
Now, what can we do? The answer is Allyship. Allyship is crucial because it involves individuals actively supporting and advocating for marginalized groups.
This presentation will focus on Allyship and how you can support a positive change, foster inclusivity, and contribute to a more equitable environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Barriers: A Strategic Framework for Collaborative Governance in Software</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/breaking-barriers-a-strategic-framework-for-collaborative-governance-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/breaking-barriers-a-strategic-framework-for-collaborative-governance-in-software/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative governance in software is challenging. This presentation focuses on stakeholder participation which seems limited to those with the technical acumen, tooling expertise, and positions of influence. Yet, evidence shows that great collaboration is dependent on quality divergent thinking balanced with quality convergent thinking. This presentation lays out a strategic framework that curates broader participation by leveraging a landscape of networks and communication channels.
Governance in software development tends to exclude valuable insights from individuals outside the technical sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Diverse Global Community: Taking Your Local Community to the Global Stage</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-diverse-global-community-taking-your-local-community-to-the-global-stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-diverse-global-community-taking-your-local-community-to-the-global-stage/</guid>
      <description>In an increasingly interconnected world, the importance of building diverse and inclusive global communities cannot be overstated. This topic explores the journey of taking a local community and expanding its reach to become a vibrant and diverse global community. By examining strategies, best practices, examples of some successful Chinese opensource communities, this session will provide valuable insights into fostering inclusivity, cultural exchange, and collaboration on a global scale.
Participants will gain a deeper understanding of the challenges and opportunities involved in transitioning a local community to the global stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community census: Understanding users &amp; maintainer personas with a community survey</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/community-census-understanding-users-maintainer-personas-with-a-community-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/community-census-understanding-users-maintainer-personas-with-a-community-survey/</guid>
      <description>It takes a village to run an open source project successfully. A village is usually run by its citizens and governed by some elected officials. In open source we call the citizens &amp;ldquo;users&amp;rdquo; and the people in charge of a project &amp;ldquo;maintainers&amp;rdquo;. To understand the health and sustainability of a project we should take a closer look at the community and not necessarily the code in the first place.
To understand their demographics a village can run a census.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding &#39;Community Over Code&#39;</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</guid>
      <description>At the Community Over Code Europe 2024, the annual conference of the Apache Software Foundation, join us for an insightful session on understanding the core principle of &amp;lsquo;Community Over Code&amp;rsquo;. This talk will delve into how this philosophy shapes the foundation&amp;rsquo;s approach to software development. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the significance of prioritizing a collaborative, inclusive community and how this fosters innovation and sustainability in open source projects. Attendees will learn about the practical implications of this ethos in Apache&amp;rsquo;s day-to-day operations and its impact on the broader open-source ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation to Use Open Source Design Templates</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/documentation-to-use-open-source-design-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/documentation-to-use-open-source-design-templates/</guid>
      <description>In this session, I share best practices on the way to create bar raising documentation to guide users to use Figma and GitHub templates. To scale best practices in UX Research, designers of open source software create various design artifacts that can help software builders use and improve on the open source code and curated experience offerings. In this talk, I offer examples of how OpenSearch creates process of research that can scale, the process of documentation and create templates that designers and developers in the open source community can utilize in developing experiences for their users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Diversity in the community:The Apache Software Foundation&#39;s Mentorship</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-diversity/</guid>
      <description>The session will highlight the strategies employed by Apache to foster a more diverse and inclusive environment, emphasizing the importance of mentorship in nurturing new talents and perspectives. This approach not only enriches the Apache community ecosystem but also ensures that it reflects the wide array of users it serves. Attendees will gain insights into the practical steps for implementing similar programs and the profound impact of inclusivity on technology development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Inclusivity: Apache Airflow&#39;s Impact on Outreachy</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-inclusivity-apache-airflow-s-impact-on-outreachy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-inclusivity-apache-airflow-s-impact-on-outreachy/</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, we will delve into the important role that Apache Airflow plays in the Outreachy program and its broader influence in closing inclusion gaps within the open source community. We will explore the success stories and transformative experiences of Outreachy contributors, emphasizing how this open source project has created opportunities for people from diverse backgrounds. Our discussion will focus on the power of open source initiatives like Apache Airflow to foster a more inclusive and accessible technology ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Algorithms, Licensing Impasses: The Intersection of Free Software and AI openness</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/ethical-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/ethical-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>The significance of responsible and ethical AI systems has gained immense prominence on the global stage, underscoring the escalating recognition of its far-reaching impact on societies worldwide. Lately, diverse groups and individuals have transitioned from relying solely on Free Software licenses for their projects to pioneering new forms of licensing solutions which impose restrictions related to fields of endeavour, behaviour, community management and commercial practices. This practice has now spilled over to creation of suo moto ethics codes for AI, leading to creation of licenses with restrictive characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing the Tech Ecosystem through Community Participation.</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/influencing-the-tech-ecosystem-through-community-participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/influencing-the-tech-ecosystem-through-community-participation/</guid>
      <description>Open source has widely grown to allow different tech career paths to enhance projects with their skills and provide jobs for those interested in working with open source. Open source contribution programs provide opportunities for interested individuals to become professionals.
Outreachy is a paid and remote internship OS program that empowers, grows talents, and prepares them for career growth. Outreachy provides internships to people subject to systemic bias and impacted by underrepresentation in the technical industry where they are living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Apache Software Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</guid>
      <description>This talk delves into the inner workings of the Apache Software Foundation board, shedding light on its workings and the responsibilities of its board members. Attendees will gain a comprehensive understanding of the ASF board&amp;rsquo;s governance structure, decision-making processes, and its crucial role in overseeing one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest groups of open-source communities. Drawing from real-life experiences, the speaker will share personal insights, challenges faced, and the rewarding aspects of contributing to ASF&amp;rsquo;s mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing In The Open, Managing Contributions: The challenges of OSPO developers management</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-in-the-open-managing-contributions-the-challenges-of-ospo-developers-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-in-the-open-managing-contributions-the-challenges-of-ospo-developers-management/</guid>
      <description>Managing an Open Source Program Office (OSPO) team is undoubtedly a unique experience. In this talk I will discuss the unique challenges and best practices for managing software developers in an OSPO environment. I will cover topics such as managing remote teams, maintaining the career progression of OSPO developers, fostering a culture of collaboration and collaborating with the open source community. I will also explore the role of performance metrics in managing software developers in an OSPO, how to align those metrics withe the goals of the organisation and how to help developers balance the needs of the organisation with the needs of the open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Measuring the Impact of Community Events</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/redhat/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/redhat/</guid>
      <description>One of the mainstays of the open source ecosystem are community events. Open Source Summit, All Things Open, Community Over Code&amp;hellip; all examples of community events with vitality and influence within open source. But unlike more commercially focused events, community events are not as simple to measure in terms of benefits to organizations that participate. Without sales leads or conversions, how does a commercial organization measure the gains of participation? And for community projects, what&amp;rsquo;s the return on investment in running a booth or giving talks at such events?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship programs. Growing new team and community leaders</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/mentorship-programs-growing-new-team-and-community-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/mentorship-programs-growing-new-team-and-community-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Mentorship and outreach programs are often considered as side projects. Although they are a nice way to spend time and have some fun, one may say they rarely add new long-term contributors to your company project or a community. Is it true? Is it even the main goal? Or is it about team bonding and growing new maintainers and community leaders?
Let’s talk about organizing mentorship programs so that they help to grow your current community and contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach: The Two-Way Street of Open Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/outreach-the-two-way-street-of-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/outreach-the-two-way-street-of-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>There are millions of open source projects people can use and contribute to. Why yours?
Developing an open source project that is valuable to many and widely accepted in an industry requires a lot of care and feeding – and more than just code. Whether your project is brand new or been around for decades, you need to explain why other people should take the time to learn, use, and potentially contribute to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretend it’s a Movie: How to Build Excitement for Your Apache Project</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/pretend-its-a-movie-how-to-build-excitement-for-your-apache-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/pretend-its-a-movie-how-to-build-excitement-for-your-apache-project/</guid>
      <description>How do you explain your Apache project to people who don’t even know how to download apps onto their phones – and still manage to get them excited about what you’re working on? It’s simple: pretend you’re talking about a movie.
The problem isn’t the project, but how we’ve been talking about them. And now we’re going to fix that.
In this talk, discover how to completely change the narrative about discussing Apache and open source by not actually talking about open source or Apache&amp;hellip;but instead using the same principles that marketers use to create excitement around a movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking with management about open source</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/talking-with-management-about-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/talking-with-management-about-open-source/</guid>
      <description>For those of us who already know how important open source is, it can be challenging to persuasively make the case to management, because we assume that everyone already knows the basics. This can work against us, confusing our audience and making us come across as condescending or concerned about irrelevant lofty philosophical points.
In this talk, we take it back to the basics. What does management actually need to know about open source, why it matters, and how to make decisions about consuming open source, contributing to open source, and open sourcing company code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the power of Asynchronous Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleash-the-power-of-asynchronous-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleash-the-power-of-asynchronous-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>The Asynchronous Decision Making techniques commonly used in open source projects enable efficient remote collaboration, in teams which have no boss, no schedule and often no cultural consistency yet produce world-changing software.
These very efficient collaboration techniques can even work without computers and apply to most types of projects, not just software development.
This talk describes the key elements and tools of the Asynchronous Decision Making process, based on more than twenty five years of experience in Open Source projects, as well as examples from federated governments, which, interestingly, work in a similar way.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
