<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Incubator on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/tracks/incubator/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Incubator on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/tracks/incubator/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Your Community Engagement with Apache Answer</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-your-community-engagement-with-apache-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-your-community-engagement-with-apache-answer/</guid>
      <description>Q&amp;amp;A is one of the most effective ways to obtain knowledge, build connections, and create interaction. In open-source communities, Q&amp;amp;A is particularly crucial. It not only provides a platform for users and developers to collaboratively tackle technical issues and clarify uncertainties but also enhances the sharing and circulation of knowledge. By helping each other in resolving issues, community members forge stronger bonds and jointly advance their projects. Additionally, a robust Q&amp;amp;A system attracts new members, injecting fresh perspectives and energy into the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is it So Hard...</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-is-it-so-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-is-it-so-hard/</guid>
      <description>to submit patches to a podling?
to release code to the public?
to maintain trademarks for a podling?
to become a committer on a podling?
This talk explains what common barriers are to accomplishing objectives of people and projects. It explains why The ASF has:
licensing requirements for code submissions and releases,
signing and checksums, download protocols,
voting requirements for releases and project membership,
trademark requirements for web sites and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
