<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kanchana Welagedara on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/kanchana-welagedara/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kanchana Welagedara on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/kanchana-welagedara/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Decoding &#39;Community Over Code&#39;</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</guid>
      <description>At the Community Over Code Europe 2024, the annual conference of the Apache Software Foundation, join us for an insightful session on understanding the core principle of &amp;lsquo;Community Over Code&amp;rsquo;. This talk will delve into how this philosophy shapes the foundation&amp;rsquo;s approach to software development. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the significance of prioritizing a collaborative, inclusive community and how this fosters innovation and sustainability in open source projects. Attendees will learn about the practical implications of this ethos in Apache&amp;rsquo;s day-to-day operations and its impact on the broader open-source ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Diversity in the community:The Apache Software Foundation&#39;s Mentorship</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-diversity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-diversity/</guid>
      <description>The session will highlight the strategies employed by Apache to foster a more diverse and inclusive environment, emphasizing the importance of mentorship in nurturing new talents and perspectives. This approach not only enriches the Apache community ecosystem but also ensures that it reflects the wide array of users it serves. Attendees will gain insights into the practical steps for implementing similar programs and the profound impact of inclusivity on technology development.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
