<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gláucia Esppenchutz on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/glaucia-esppenchutz/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gláucia Esppenchutz on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/glaucia-esppenchutz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Allyship - We need you to power up Diversity</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/allyship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/allyship/</guid>
      <description>Open-source technologies play a significant role in driving technological advancements, fostering collaboration, and encouraging innovation. The Apache Software Foundation is a prominent nonprofit organization in this realm. Nevertheless, unlocking the full potential of these projects necessitates a commitment to embracing diversity and inclusion.
Now, what can we do? The answer is Allyship. Allyship is crucial because it involves individuals actively supporting and advocating for marginalized groups.
This presentation will focus on Allyship and how you can support a positive change, foster inclusivity, and contribute to a more equitable environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Docs &amp; Training: Empowering communities through accessible Docs &amp; training material</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-docs-training-empowering-communities-through-accessible-docs-training-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-docs-training-empowering-communities-through-accessible-docs-training-material/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving landscape of open source projects, the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) stands at the forefront of innovation and community-driven development. Two of its young projects, Apache Training and Apache Wayang, are working on an exciting journey of expansion and inclusivity.
This session is dedicated to showcasing how these projects are opening their doors to a broader audience, including non-technical individuals, thereby fostering a more diverse and robust community, which helps the ASF to continue in solving some of the world’s tech problems by bringing people together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
