<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:51:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate the 25th Anniversary of the ASF!</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/anniversary/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Software Foundation (ASF), composed by volunteer developers, stewards and incubators of more than 320 active Open Source projects and initiatives is celebrating its 25th anniversary in 2024!
The ASF stewards 299M+ lines of code in 2,500+ Apache repositories across 320+ active projects. Each Apache Project is overseen by a Project Management Committee (PMC) that guides its day-to-day operations, including community development and product releases. Across the ASF, there are 209 committees managing 294 projects, including 5 special committees and 24 incubating podlings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the venue</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/venue/</guid>
      <description>This year the beautiful city of Bratislava will welcome the ASF Conference. We chose this city for its charm, history, attractions and the many possibilities to get there so that your Community Over Code experience will be memorable both inside and outside the venue.
Bratislava lies along the beautiful blue Danube, arguably the most important river in central Europe and a national boundary between Slovakia, Hungary and Austria. You can actually reach the two neighboring capitals by boat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Submit your proposal</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/cfp-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/cfp-open/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s back and it&amp;rsquo;s new!
We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that the first edition of Community over Code Europe (formerly known as ApacheCon EU) will be held at the Radisson Blu Carlton Hotel in Bratislava, Slovakia from June 03-05, 2024! This eagerly anticipated event will be our first live EU conference since 2019.
The Call for Presentations (CFP) for Community Over Code EU 2024 is now open at https://sessionize.com/coceu-2024.
We welcome submissions on any topic related to the Apache Software Foundation, Apache projects, or the communities around those projects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
