<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 13:51:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scholarships</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/scholarships/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/scholarships/</guid>
      <description>Apply for the Travel Assistance Committee Scholarship! The Travel Assistance Committee provides financial assistance with travel (air fares or train tickets), accommodation during the conference and conference fees to those who would otherwise be unable to attend various ASF related events.
The Committee has limited finances and as a consequence, only a few places are available for each Apache event. Applicants should have valid reasons for attending ASF related events that are of benefit to both the applicant and the ASF, and to open source as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity &amp; Inclusion</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/diversity-&amp;-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/diversity-&amp;-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>Merge with a diverse and inclusive ASF EUniverse As simple as it sounds, we want us all to merge with the ASF Universe. Regardless of geography, gender, sexual orientation, dis/ability, race, ethnicity, age, religion, economic status or any other characteristic. We believe that every difference, even the smallest ones, not only make everyone unique, but also enrich the community. Diversity gives us the opportunity to keep learning and growing as human beings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate the 25th ASF Anniversary!</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/anniversary/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/blog/anniversary/</guid>
      <description>The Apache Software Foundation (ASF), composed by volunteer developers, stewards and incubators of more than 320 active Open Source projects and initiatives is celebrating its 25th anniversary in 2024!
The ASF stewards 299M+ lines of code in 2,500+ Apache repositories across 320+ active projects. Each Apache Project is overseen by a Project Management Committee (PMC) that guides its day-to-day operations, including community development and product releases. Across the ASF, there are 209 committees managing 294 projects, including 5 special committees and 24 incubating podlings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the venue</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2023 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/venue/</guid>
      <description>Where to Stay Hotels Walking time Room rate Booking link Radisson Blu Carlton - €134.55 COC2024 reservation link
(promotional code only works for dates between June 1-6, expires on May 10) Park Inn by Radisson Danube Bratislava 5 min €128.50 COC24 reservation link
(promotional code only works for dates between June 1-6) This year the beautiful city of Bratislava will welcome the ASF Conference. We chose this city for its charm, history, attractions and the many possibilities to get there so that your Community Over Code experience will be memorable both inside and outside the venue.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
