<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Justin Mclean on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/justin-mclean/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Justin Mclean on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/justin-mclean/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Gravitino: A multi-regional, geo-distributed meta datalake</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/gravitino/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/gravitino/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to a presentation on Gravitino! Managing metadata can be complex and time-consuming, but Gravitino offers the ultimate solution. It provides a single source of truth for multi-regional data with geo-distributed architecture support. This allows you to store and manage your data in one place, accessible from anywhere globally. With unified data and AI asset management, you get centralized security and data access management, making data protection easier. Gravitino helps you focus more on your data by simplifying tasks and offering these benefits:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Apache Software Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</guid>
      <description>This talk delves into the inner workings of the Apache Software Foundation board, shedding light on its workings and the responsibilities of its board members. Attendees will gain a comprehensive understanding of the ASF board&amp;rsquo;s governance structure, decision-making processes, and its crucial role in overseeing one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest groups of open-source communities. Drawing from real-life experiences, the speaker will share personal insights, challenges faced, and the rewarding aspects of contributing to ASF&amp;rsquo;s mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Podling Releases: Achieving Success in the Apache Incubator</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-podling-releases-achieving-success-in-the-apache-incubator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-podling-releases-achieving-success-in-the-apache-incubator/</guid>
      <description>Discover the keys to success when releasing a podling within the Apache Incubator. This talk explores the crucial aspects that the incubator PMC looks for in every release, providing practical tips to pass the IPMC vote and move your project closer to graduation.
Learn about the latest incubator and ASF policies, recent updates you may have missed, and the legal requirements of open source licenses. Gain insights into assembling your NOTICE and LICENSE files effectively, while understanding the reasoning behind specific practices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
