<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Community Over Code EU 2024 sessions on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Community Over Code EU 2024 sessions on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>4 tricks that help you leverage your Airflow pipelines</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/4-tricks-that-help-you-leverage-your-airflow-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/4-tricks-that-help-you-leverage-your-airflow-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>In this insightful presentation, Aliaksandr will unveil four ingenious tricks to maximize your Apache Airflow experience in the realm of data engineering. Starting with the power of leveraging CSV files to effortlessly create versatile DAGs, Aliaksandr will demonstrate how this flexibility can streamline your pipeline development process. Moving forward, the audience will learn how Google Sheets can be harnessed as a dynamic tool for DAG creation, opening up opportunities for collaboration among team members of varying Airflow proficiency levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Hands-On Introduction to the Kubernetes Gateway API with Apache APISIX</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/a-hands-on-introduction-to-the-kubernetes-gateway-api-with-apache-apisix/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/a-hands-on-introduction-to-the-kubernetes-gateway-api-with-apache-apisix/</guid>
      <description>Why do you need another API to handle external traffic when you have the stable Kubernetes Ingress API and dozens of implementations? What problems of the Ingress API does the new Gateway API solve? Does this mean the end of the Ingress API?
In this short talk, Navendu will answer these questions by exploring how Gateway APIs evolved and solved the shortcomings of the Ingress API with hands-on examples using Apache APISIX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Arrow: An On-Point Addition to Any Lakehouse</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-arrow-an-on-point-addition-to-any-lakehouse/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-arrow-an-on-point-addition-to-any-lakehouse/</guid>
      <description>Apache Arrow has become a de-facto standard for representing large datasets and a very useful tool in any modern data engineering stack. While it allows different technologies to better communicate and share data, the ecosystem around it enables much more!
In this talk we’ll cover how Arrow interacts with Apache Spark - from allowing PySpark to interoperate with other Python data libraries, to building data-driven applications with the recent addition of Spark Connect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel Takes Charge of Over 1000 Interfaces in a Seamless Transition from Oracle SOA Suite</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-camel-takes-charge-of-over-1000-interfaces-in-a-seamless-transition-from-oracle-soa-suite/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-camel-takes-charge-of-over-1000-interfaces-in-a-seamless-transition-from-oracle-soa-suite/</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel leads a seamless transition, taking control of 1000+ interfaces from Oracle SOA Suite.
Over the last two years, we have driven forward the integration of all retail systems from a centralised and proprietary system into a microservice-oriented architecture based on Apache Camel and Openshift.
The previously centralised gateways are now independent interfaces.
The challenge here was to lift the countless proprietary implementations to a system that is open to all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Docs &amp; Training: Empowering communities through accessible Docs &amp; training material</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-docs-training-empowering-communities-through-accessible-docs-training-material/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-docs-training-empowering-communities-through-accessible-docs-training-material/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving landscape of open source projects, the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) stands at the forefront of innovation and community-driven development. Two of its young projects, Apache Training and Apache Wayang, are working on an exciting journey of expansion and inclusivity.
This session is dedicated to showcasing how these projects are opening their doors to a broader audience, including non-technical individuals, thereby fostering a more diverse and robust community, which helps the ASF to continue in solving some of the world’s tech problems by bringing people together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Iceberg Planning Explained</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-iceberg-planning-explained/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-iceberg-planning-explained/</guid>
      <description>A critical aspect of any table format is the rapid identification of files relevant for a query irrespective of the underlying data volume. The focus of this presentation is on the job planning process in Apache Iceberg, highlighting its efficiency and ability to scale to tens of millions of files. This session will explain how the project leverages a hybrid strategy for planning jobs, seamlessly transitioning between local and distributed execution for optimal performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Mynewt - connected RTOS - project overview</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-mynewt-connected-rtos-project-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-mynewt-connected-rtos-project-overview/</guid>
      <description>Apache Mynewt is a community-driven, permissively licensed Open Source initiative for constrained, embedded devices and applications. It provides foundational RTOS, middleware (secure bootloader, filesystem, networking stack, device management) and tooling.
This presentation will cover history and overall state of the project, its architecture and selected components (eg Bluetooth stack). Will discuss already available features as well additions planned in near future.
Last but not least, state of community will be presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Ratis - A High Performance Raft Library</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-ratis-a-high-performance-raft-library/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-ratis-a-high-performance-raft-library/</guid>
      <description>Apache Ratis is an open source Java library for the Raft Consensus Protocol. Raft is being used successfully as an alternative to Paxos to implement a consistently replicated log. Raft is proven to be safe and is designed to be simpler to understand. Ratis is a high performance implementation of Raft. Apache Ozone, Apache IoTDB and Alluxio use Apache Ratis for providing high availability and replicating raw data.
Ratis implements all the standard Raft features, including leader election, log replication, membership change and log compaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache SIS library for geospatial applications</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-sis-library-for-geospatial-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/apache-sis-library-for-geospatial-applications/</guid>
      <description>Geospatial data are ubiquitous, but the difficulty of handling them accurately is often under-estimated. Various projects implement their own routines for performing geospatial operations, but not always with awareness about the pitfalls of simple approaches. This talk will present some of the difficulties in mapping &amp;ldquo;real world&amp;rdquo; to digital data. Then we will present some international standards published jointly by the Open Geospatial Consortium (OGC) and the International Organization for Standardization (ISO).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecting Applications With Multiple Open-Source Big Data Technologies</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/architecting-applications-with-multiple-open-source-big-data-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/architecting-applications-with-multiple-open-source-big-data-technologies/</guid>
      <description>When I started as the Instaclustr Technology Evangelist 7 years ago, I already had a background in computer science R&amp;amp;D and thought I knew a few things about architecting complex distributed systems. But it was still challenging to learn multiple new Apache (and other) Big Data technologies and build and scale realistic demonstration applications for domains such as IoT/logistics, fintech, anomaly detection, geospatial data, data pipelines and a drone delivery application - with streaming machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking Barriers: A Strategic Framework for Collaborative Governance in Software</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/breaking-barriers-a-strategic-framework-for-collaborative-governance-in-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/breaking-barriers-a-strategic-framework-for-collaborative-governance-in-software/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative governance in software is challenging. This presentation focuses on stakeholder participation which seems limited to those with the technical acumen, tooling expertise, and positions of influence. Yet, evidence shows that great collaboration is dependent on quality divergent thinking balanced with quality convergent thinking. This presentation lays out a strategic framework that curates broader participation by leveraging a landscape of networks and communication channels.
Governance in software development tends to exclude valuable insights from individuals outside the technical sphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Diverse Global Community: Taking Your Local Community to the Global Stage</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-diverse-global-community-taking-your-local-community-to-the-global-stage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-diverse-global-community-taking-your-local-community-to-the-global-stage/</guid>
      <description>In an increasingly interconnected world, the importance of building diverse and inclusive global communities cannot be overstated. This topic explores the journey of taking a local community and expanding its reach to become a vibrant and diverse global community. By examining strategies, best practices, examples of some successful Chinese opensource communities, this session will provide valuable insights into fostering inclusivity, cultural exchange, and collaboration on a global scale.
Participants will gain a deeper understanding of the challenges and opportunities involved in transitioning a local community to the global stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Kubernetes Operator for Apache Flink in Java</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-kubernetes-operator-for-apache-flink-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-a-kubernetes-operator-for-apache-flink-in-java/</guid>
      <description>Managing complex applications such as data processing systems on Kubernetes is a formidable challenge even for the most seasoned engineers. Whether you want to build applications that operate themselves or provision infrastructure from Java code, Kubernetes Operators are the way to go.
The Java Operator SDK is a production-ready framework that makes implementing Kubernetes Operators in Java easy. We will give you a run-down on the basics of operators and implementing one from scratch in Java and why this library may be the right choice for your project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Healthy Developer Communities: A Versatile Framework for Success</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-healthy-developer-communities-a-versatile-framework-for-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-healthy-developer-communities-a-versatile-framework-for-success/</guid>
      <description>As developer communities grow both in size and number, it can be easy to lose sight of the importance of community health in the development process. Most tech communities guide their community efforts and future work based on NPS scores and feedback forms. Though well intended, these methods do not provide a full view of the current status of their community members or guarantee they are moving towards a direction that benefits their members or fulfills their needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building services and pipelines for real-world data</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-services-and-pipelines-for-real-world-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/building-services-and-pipelines-for-real-world-data/</guid>
      <description>In the speech &amp;ldquo;Building Services and Pipelines for Real-World Data,&amp;rdquo; the speaker, an experienced professional in analytics services, delves into the complexities and challenges of extracting meaningful insights from chaotic, real-world data. The speech will address practical scenarios, from analyzing trading transactions to interpreting geolocation data, highlighting the difficulties in aligning data with real-world events and developing reliable analytical services. The speaker will share firsthand experiences and solutions for creating effective data pipelines and services, emphasizing the importance of adaptable architectures and strategies in data transformation and interpretation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra CIDR filtering authorizer (CEP-33)</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/cassandra-cidr-filtering-authorizer-cep-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/cassandra-cidr-filtering-authorizer-cep-33/</guid>
      <description>As Cassandra clusters and users onboarding to multi cloud platforms, users may access Cassandra clusters from on-premise and from various cloud platforms. Admins may need to restrict certain users/teams to access from certain IP ranges, aka, CIDR groups. Also, may need to restrict superusers credentials usage from third party clouds.
CIDR filtering authorizer provides capability for admins to configure allow or disallow users access from different CIDR groups, which can help in preventing misuse of copied or hacked credentials.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying Iris flowers with Groovy, Deep Learning, and GraalVM</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/classifying-iris-flowers-with-groovy-deep-learning-and-graalvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/classifying-iris-flowers-with-groovy-deep-learning-and-graalvm/</guid>
      <description>This talk looks at using Groovy for a well-known data-science problem: classifying Iris flowers. It involves solving this problem using the latest deep-learning neural network technologies and has the option of using GraalVM for blazing speed. Groovy provides a data-science environment with the simplicity of Python but using Java-like syntax and your favourite JVM technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Community census: Understanding users &amp; maintainer personas with a community survey</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/community-census-understanding-users-maintainer-personas-with-a-community-survey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/community-census-understanding-users-maintainer-personas-with-a-community-survey/</guid>
      <description>It takes a village to run an open source project successfully. A village is usually run by its citizens and governed by some elected officials. In open source we call the citizens &amp;ldquo;users&amp;rdquo; and the people in charge of a project &amp;ldquo;maintainers&amp;rdquo;. To understand the health and sustainability of a project we should take a closer look at the community and not necessarily the code in the first place.
To understand their demographics a village can run a census.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data enrichment patterns with Apache Flink</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/data-enrichment-patterns-with-apache-flink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/data-enrichment-patterns-with-apache-flink/</guid>
      <description>Data enrichment is a critical step in stream processing. Real-time enrichment of streaming data with contextual information adds missing information, improves accuracy, increases trustworthiness, and facilitates better decision-making. Contextual data can be static or dynamic and obtained in various ways - APIs, databases, files and even as a stream. While there are multiple design patterns to perform data enrichment, it is not always obvious when one pattern is preferred over the other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Symphony: Orchestrating Insights in Fintech</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/data-symphony-orchestrating-insights-in-fintech/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/data-symphony-orchestrating-insights-in-fintech/</guid>
      <description>Uncover the pivotal role of a Data Science Product Manager as they conduct a data-driven symphony in a high-volume Fintech environment.
In the world of product management, the role of a Data Science Product Manager stands out as a conductor orchestrating a symphony of insights. Join me in this session as I share firsthand experiences from my journey as a Data Science Product Manager at PayPal, delving into the challenges, successes, and failures that have shaped my approach to leading products in a data-rich environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decoding &#39;Community Over Code&#39;</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/decoding-community-over-code/</guid>
      <description>At the Community Over Code Europe 2024, the annual conference of the Apache Software Foundation, join us for an insightful session on understanding the core principle of &amp;lsquo;Community Over Code&amp;rsquo;. This talk will delve into how this philosophy shapes the foundation&amp;rsquo;s approach to software development. We&amp;rsquo;ll explore the significance of prioritizing a collaborative, inclusive community and how this fosters innovation and sustainability in open source projects. Attendees will learn about the practical implications of this ethos in Apache&amp;rsquo;s day-to-day operations and its impact on the broader open-source ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Documentation to Use Open Source Design Templates</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/documentation-to-use-open-source-design-templates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/documentation-to-use-open-source-design-templates/</guid>
      <description>In this session, I share best practices on the way to create bar raising documentation to guide users to use Figma and GitHub templates. To scale best practices in UX Research, designers of open source software create various design artifacts that can help software builders use and improve on the open source code and curated experience offerings. In this talk, I offer examples of how OpenSearch creates process of research that can scale, the process of documentation and create templates that designers and developers in the open source community can utilize in developing experiences for their users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing for sustainability, what open source did for software</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-asin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-asin/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of sustainability, grassroots initiatives often emerge as powerful catalysts for change, driven by the collective wisdom of practitioners.
Our organization, a coalition of hundreds of software practitioners, embodies this ethos, operating on the principles of consensus and practical action. The result? Tangible solutions that directly foster meaningful change.
Enter Impact Framework, an open-source tool designed to quantify the environmental impact of software. It takes observations you can easily gather from running systems such as CPU utilisation, page views, installs, prompts and induces them into environmental impacts like carbon, waste, water.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient, Low Latency Ingestion to Large Tables via Apache Flink and Apache Iceberg</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/efficient-low-latency-ingestion-to-large-tables-via-apache-flink-and-apache-iceberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/efficient-low-latency-ingestion-to-large-tables-via-apache-flink-and-apache-iceberg/</guid>
      <description>One of the primary challenges of data ingestion is the tradeoff between the latency of data availability for the downstream systems and the extent to which data is optimised for efficient reading. When ingesting continuous incoming data streams with low latency, Apache Flink is a data processing engine that shines. Apache Iceberg is one of the most popular table formats for large tables. To get the best of both worlds, and continuously ingest data and see near real-time changes to tables queried by various engines, tight integration is needed between these two Apache projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elevating Scalable Object Storage: A Comprehensive Exploration of Ozone’s Trailblazing Capabilities</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/elevating-scalable-object-storage-a-comprehensive-exploration-of-ozones-trailblazing-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/elevating-scalable-object-storage-a-comprehensive-exploration-of-ozones-trailblazing-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>In the era of explosive data growth, scalability is paramount for any storage solution. This abstract focuses on the scalability aspects of Apache Ozone, a distributed object storage system designed to handle the ever-increasing demands of modern data-intensive applications.
The session will commence with an up-to-date overview of Apache Ozone, providing insights into its current state, recent enhancements, and its pivotal role in addressing the evolving needs of organizations. Attendees will gain a comprehensive understanding of how Apache Ozone offers scalable, high-performance, and future-ready solutions tailored to the challenges posed by today&amp;rsquo;s data-intensive applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empowering Inclusivity: Apache Airflow&#39;s Impact on Outreachy</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-inclusivity-apache-airflow-s-impact-on-outreachy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/empowering-inclusivity-apache-airflow-s-impact-on-outreachy/</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, we will delve into the important role that Apache Airflow plays in the Outreachy program and its broader influence in closing inclusion gaps within the open source community. We will explore the success stories and transformative experiences of Outreachy contributors, emphasizing how this open source project has created opportunities for people from diverse backgrounds. Our discussion will focus on the power of open source initiatives like Apache Airflow to foster a more inclusive and accessible technology ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Flexibility and Productivity with Access Patterns and Storage-Agnostic Abstractions</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-flexibility-and-productivity-with-access-patterns-and-storage-agnostic-abstractions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-flexibility-and-productivity-with-access-patterns-and-storage-agnostic-abstractions/</guid>
      <description>This session will introduce a platform created to bridge the existing gaps in data management while removing some of the complexities in existing Big Data ecosystem. The platform is built around a comprehensive data model describing structured entities and their relations. The model is consistently applied across three abstract types of storages - streaming (e.g. Apache Kafka, Google Cloud PubSub), batch (e.g. Hadoop HDFS, S3, Google Cloud Storage) and random-access (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhancing Your Community Engagement with Apache Answer</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-your-community-engagement-with-apache-answer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/enhancing-your-community-engagement-with-apache-answer/</guid>
      <description>Q&amp;amp;A is one of the most effective ways to obtain knowledge, build connections, and create interaction. In open-source communities, Q&amp;amp;A is particularly crucial. It not only provides a platform for users and developers to collaboratively tackle technical issues and clarify uncertainties but also enhances the sharing and circulation of knowledge. By helping each other in resolving issues, community members forge stronger bonds and jointly advance their projects. Additionally, a robust Q&amp;amp;A system attracts new members, injecting fresh perspectives and energy into the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethical Algorithms, Licensing Impasses: The Intersection of Free Software and AI openness</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/ethical-algorithms/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/ethical-algorithms/</guid>
      <description>The significance of responsible and ethical AI systems has gained immense prominence on the global stage, underscoring the escalating recognition of its far-reaching impact on societies worldwide. Lately, diverse groups and individuals have transitioned from relying solely on Free Software licenses for their projects to pioneering new forms of licensing solutions which impose restrictions related to fields of endeavour, behaviour, community management and commercial practices. This practice has now spilled over to creation of suo moto ethics codes for AI, leading to creation of licenses with restrictive characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EU policies and regulations affecting open source specialists working in OSPOs</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/eu-policies-and-regulations-affecting-open-source-specialists-working-in-ospos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/eu-policies-and-regulations-affecting-open-source-specialists-working-in-ospos/</guid>
      <description>The panel will discuss how EU legislation affects the daily work of open source operations (upstream contribution to open source projects, open source compliance, etc) focusing on how these laws impact open source professionals working in OSPOs or similar entities. Panelists will cover some of the recent policy updates, the challenges of staying compliant when managing open source contribution and usage within organizations, and their personal experiences in adapting to the changing European regulatory environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolving Fintech Landscapes: Driving Business Innovation with Fineract</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/evolving-fintech-landscapes-driving-business-innovation-with-fineract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/evolving-fintech-landscapes-driving-business-innovation-with-fineract/</guid>
      <description>This session explores Fineract&amp;rsquo;s impact on banking transformation in fintech. It analyzes motivators driving core banking system changes, addressing challenges and innovative solutions.
From a client-focused view, it details how Fineract addresses banking sector needs, emphasizing adaptability and strategic advantages globally.
Real success cases and their metrics will demonstrate Fineract&amp;rsquo;s positive influence, driving innovation across financial landscapes. It also discusses regional fintech challenges and the potential solutions with Fineract as a fundamental piece.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fineract - Advanced payment allocation</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/fineract-advanced-payment-allocation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/fineract-advanced-payment-allocation/</guid>
      <description>Since the first repayment strategy got introduced, many followed, but there was one thing common in them:
They were hard coding the allocation rules for each transaction type.
By introducing - part of the 1.9.0 release - the &amp;ldquo;Advanced payment allocation&amp;rdquo; the idea was to have a repayment strategy which was:
Supporting dynamic configuration of the allocation rules for transaction types
Supporting configuration of more fine-grained allocation rules for future installments</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fineract scalability improvements</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/fineract-scalability-improvements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/fineract-scalability-improvements/</guid>
      <description>In this presentation we delve into infrastructure optimization options for supporting the scalability of Fineract.
Key highlights of the session include:
Performance testing: Exploring the newly-introduced capabilities of Fineract that enable drilling down to performance bottlenecks during development and in production.
Performance improvements: Showing infrastructure and configuration changes that can improve Fineract&amp;rsquo;s response times and throughput under high-load scenarios.
Scalability improvements: Presenting improvements on Fineract&amp;rsquo;s scalability capabilities, focusing on infrastructure-based scaling velocity improvements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gatekeep iceberg data quality with Apache Toree and airflow</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/gatekeep-iceberg-data-quality-with-apache-toree-and-airflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/gatekeep-iceberg-data-quality-with-apache-toree-and-airflow/</guid>
      <description>Data quality plays a crucial role in data engineering to enable efficient and insightful data pipelines at scale. In this session, we will leverage Apache Iceberg as the scalable table format with ACID guarantee, Apache Toree’s interactive computation capabilities and orchestrate the automated data workflow on Apache Airflow. We will start by talking about how iceberg can use its column level statistics stored in metadata for efficient and reliable data quality validation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with the Micronaut® Framework</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/getting-started-with-the-micronaut-r-framework/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/getting-started-with-the-micronaut-r-framework/</guid>
      <description>In this session, Sergio del Amo introduces the Micronaut® framework and demonstrates how the Framework&amp;rsquo;s unique compile-time approach enables the development of ultra-lightweight Java applications.
Compelling aspects of the Micronaut framework include:
Develop applications with Java, Kotlin, or Apache Groovy
Sub-second startup time
Small processes that can run in as little as 10 MB of JVM heap
No runtime reflection
Dependency injection and AOP
Reflection-free serialization
A database access toolkit that uses ahead-of-time (AoT) compilation to pre-compute queries for repository interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing WebAssembly for Real-time Stateless Streaming Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/harnessing-webassembly-for-real-time-stateless-streaming-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/harnessing-webassembly-for-real-time-stateless-streaming-pipelines/</guid>
      <description>Traditionally, dealing with real-time data pipelines has involved significant overhead, even for straightforward tasks like data transformation or masking. However, in this talk, we&amp;rsquo;ll venture into the dynamic realm of WebAssembly (WASM) and discover how it can revolutionize the creation of stateless streaming pipelines within a Kafka (Redpanda) broker. These pipelines are adept at managing low-latency, high-data-volume scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hive-Iceberg - Breaking the Ice: A Closer Look at Hive-Iceberg</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/hive-iceberg-breaking-the-ice-a-closer-look-at-hive-iceberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/hive-iceberg-breaking-the-ice-a-closer-look-at-hive-iceberg/</guid>
      <description>The session will start by covering the latest developments made in hive-iceberg and followed by an overview of the work done to seamlessly integrate Hive and Iceberg. Along with a deep dive into the various cool features supported by hive-iceberg , ranging from statistics, branching tagging, compactions, concurrency and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to extend Fineract with custom modules</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/how-to-extend-fineract-with-custom-modules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/how-to-extend-fineract-with-custom-modules/</guid>
      <description>Apache Fineract has a wide range of built-in features, but most companies that integrate Fineract into their applications and services still require some customization of existing functionality or add new features. The usual approach is to fork the upstream project on Github and start right away editing the original code. This approach has a couple of drawbacks, especially that after a while of development the customization gets so complex that pulling changes from the upstream repository makes Git conflicts more likely and contributions back to the upstream project very difficult.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/3 where are we now? State of the art in our servers.</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/http-3-where-are-we-now-state-of-the-art-in-our-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/http-3-where-are-we-now-state-of-the-art-in-our-servers/</guid>
      <description>As HTTP/3 looks ready we will look to where we are with it in our servers.
The &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; HTTP/2 protocol and the corresponding TLS/SSL are common to Traffic Server, HTTP Server and Tomcat.
The presentation will shortly explain the new protocol and look to different implementation of the protocol.
Then the state of HTTP/3 in our 3 servers and how to implement HTTP/3 in them will be presented.
A small demo supporting HTTP/3 will be run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Search with Apache Solr</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/hybrid-search-with-apache-solr/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/hybrid-search-with-apache-solr/</guid>
      <description>Vector-based search gained incredible popularity in the last few years: Large Language Models fine-tuned for sentence similarity proved to be quite effective in encoding text to vectors and representing some of the semantics of sentences in a numerical form.
These vectors can be used to run a K-nearest neighbour search and look for documents/paragraphs close to the query in a n-dimensional vector space, effectively mimicking a similarity search in the semantic space (Apache Solr KNN Query Parser).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Importing KVM instances from external KVM hosts or QCOW2</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/importing-kvm-instances-from-external-kvm-hosts-or-qcow2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/importing-kvm-instances-from-external-kvm-hosts-or-qcow2/</guid>
      <description>CloudStack recently introduced a few hypervisor migration features, to help cloud operators migrate existing VM workloads into CloudStack. In this session, we are going to see how you can migrate instances from external KVM hosts to KVM hosts managed by CloudStack. Also, we are going to see how we can quickly deploy an instance from a previously prepared qcow2 image.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Increasing Adoption and Achieving Financial Inclusion through DPI</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/increasing-adoption-and-achieving-financial-inclusion-through-dpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/increasing-adoption-and-achieving-financial-inclusion-through-dpi/</guid>
      <description>The Digital Public Infrastructure movement has been gaining momentum globally as governments move to DPI-based approaches to create exponential societal outcomes within and across sectors. DPI is composed of open, interoperable technology with transparent, accountable, and participatory governance frameworks to unlock innovation and value at scale. This session will introduce how Apache projects like Fineract recognized as Digital Public Goods are having transformative impact on achieving SDGs.
Through presentation of the work Mifos has been undertaking over the past 12 months we will show how capabilities have been enhanced in Payment Hub EE combined with the power of Fineract to cover new use cases of P2G, Voucher Management and Account Mapping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Incremental snapshots/backups in KVM plugin of Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/incremental-snapshots-backups-in-kvm-plugin-of-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/incremental-snapshots-backups-in-kvm-plugin-of-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>Apache CloudStack (ACS) and KVM are a combination that many organizations decided to adopt. KVM is a widely used hypervisor with a vibrant community and support in different operating system distributions. While developing the KVM plugin functionalities, one normally tries to make use of the full potential of the hypervisor; however, while Libvirt, the toolkit used by ACS to manage KVM VMs, already supports native incremental snapshots, every volume snapshot/backup taken with ACS is a full snapshot/backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Influencing the Tech Ecosystem through Community Participation.</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/influencing-the-tech-ecosystem-through-community-participation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/influencing-the-tech-ecosystem-through-community-participation/</guid>
      <description>Open source has widely grown to allow different tech career paths to enhance projects with their skills and provide jobs for those interested in working with open source. Open source contribution programs provide opportunities for interested individuals to become professionals.
Outreachy is a paid and remote internship OS program that empowers, grows talents, and prepares them for career growth. Outreachy provides internships to people subject to systemic bias and impacted by underrepresentation in the technical industry where they are living.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside the Apache Software Foundation Board</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/inside-the-apache-software-foundation-board/</guid>
      <description>This talk delves into the inner workings of the Apache Software Foundation board, shedding light on its workings and the responsibilities of its board members. Attendees will gain a comprehensive understanding of the ASF board&amp;rsquo;s governance structure, decision-making processes, and its crucial role in overseeing one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest groups of open-source communities. Drawing from real-life experiences, the speaker will share personal insights, challenges faced, and the rewarding aspects of contributing to ASF&amp;rsquo;s mission.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration in the cloud era with Camel Quarkus</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/integration-in-the-cloud-era-with-camel-quarkus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/integration-in-the-cloud-era-with-camel-quarkus/</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel is the proven integration swiss knife for years. In today&amp;rsquo;s world of workloads moving to the cloud, the need for disparate systems to communicate remains more than ever. This context makes a Kubernetes Java stack like Quarkus a good fit to implement Camel routes.
In this session, the attendance can first expect a quick reminder about Camel Quarkus basics. Beyond, some day to day useful features will be presented via concrete examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-dirk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-dirk/</guid>
      <description>Abstract coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keynote</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-ruth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/keynote-ruth/</guid>
      <description>Abstract coming soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s see how fast Impala runs on Iceberg</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/lets-see-how-fast-impala-runs-on-iceberg/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/lets-see-how-fast-impala-runs-on-iceberg/</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a distributed massively parallel query engine designed for high-performance querying of large-scale data. There has been a long list of new features recently around supporting Apache Iceberg tables such as reading, writing, time traveling, and so on. However, in a big data environment it is also a must to be performant. Since Impala has been designed to be fast, it has its own way of reading Iceberg tables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leveraging Groovy and Apache Ignite for fast, distributed, scaleable computing and data</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/leveraging-groovy-and-apache-ignite-for-fast-distributed-scaleable-computing-and-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/leveraging-groovy-and-apache-ignite-for-fast-distributed-scaleable-computing-and-data/</guid>
      <description>Following on from the previous success of distributing Groovy tasks over an Ignite Cluster to solve oddly shaped Rubik’s cubes, we investigate further possibilities using Groovy’s concise and expressive syntax to extend Ignite. This time we take a deeper look at classloader behaviour in the JVM to distribute native Groovy closures. We also extend the Groovy REPL to give us an easy way to fire up nodes in an Ignite cluster and to query data against it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic industrial data acquisition with Apache PLC4X, TsFile and IoTDB</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/magic-industrial-data-acquisition-with-apache-plc4x-tsfile-and-iotdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/magic-industrial-data-acquisition-with-apache-plc4x-tsfile-and-iotdb/</guid>
      <description>In industrial automation, the established way of collecting data from industrial equipment has many issues. Issues for which Apache provides a number of great ways to avoid them.
In this talk, I want to demonstrate some of the issues I have seen and how we can resolve all of them with combinations of some of the amazing projects we have at Apache:
How we can use Apache TsFile to directly collect data on the hardware</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maintaining Diverse Maintainers: How to Keep Your Project Inclusive</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/maintaining-diverse-maintainers-how-to-keep-your-project-inclusive/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/maintaining-diverse-maintainers-how-to-keep-your-project-inclusive/</guid>
      <description>After maintaining open source projects for 5+ years now with diverse teams, I&amp;rsquo;ve learn some key ways to keep your open source project inclusive. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s the platforms you use, communication style, development flexibility, project promotion, or keeping contribution barrier low, there&amp;rsquo;s lots of small strategies that can be used to increase representation and community connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making Apache CloudStack market ready with a native rating solution</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/making-apache-cloudstack-market-ready-with-a-native-rating-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/making-apache-cloudstack-market-ready-with-a-native-rating-solution/</guid>
      <description>Apache CloudStack (ACS) is a solid option among known cloud orchestration systems, being on the same level as OpenStack, Azure Stack, and others. All of them address the basic needs to create and run a private cloud system; however, ACS&amp;rsquo;s users have to adopt external solutions for rating/billing the resources consumption, which is native in the other orchestration tools (e.g. OpenStack). This presentation will address the design and efforts of the ACS community to implement a native rating feature that will allow more flexibility and reduce the need for external systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing In The Open, Managing Contributions: The challenges of OSPO developers management</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-in-the-open-managing-contributions-the-challenges-of-ospo-developers-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-in-the-open-managing-contributions-the-challenges-of-ospo-developers-management/</guid>
      <description>Managing an Open Source Program Office (OSPO) team is undoubtedly a unique experience. In this talk I will discuss the unique challenges and best practices for managing software developers in an OSPO environment. I will cover topics such as managing remote teams, maintaining the career progression of OSPO developers, fostering a culture of collaboration and collaborating with the open source community. I will also explore the role of performance metrics in managing software developers in an OSPO, how to align those metrics withe the goals of the organisation and how to help developers balance the needs of the organisation with the needs of the open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing the Camel development lifecycle within VS Code</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-the-camel-development-lifecycle-within-vs-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/managing-the-camel-development-lifecycle-within-vs-code/</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel is the leading open-source integration framework that simplifies the integration of various systems and applications. There exists a comprehensive set of Tooling specifically designed to empower Camel developers in their work with Apache Camel within VS Code. These tools facilitate a seamless and efficient development experience, offering robust support and functionalities tailored to the needs of Camel developers.
In my session I would like to rely on the Extension Pack for Apache Camel which contains a set of specific extensions for Camel but also leverages the VS Code ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship programs. Growing new team and community leaders</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/mentorship-programs-growing-new-team-and-community-leaders/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/mentorship-programs-growing-new-team-and-community-leaders/</guid>
      <description>Mentorship and outreach programs are often considered as side projects. Although they are a nice way to spend time and have some fun, one may say they rarely add new long-term contributors to your company project or a community. Is it true? Is it even the main goal? Or is it about team bonding and growing new maintainers and community leaders?
Let’s talk about organizing mentorship programs so that they help to grow your current community and contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Orchestrators</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modern-data-orchestrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modern-data-orchestrators/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the tricks and best practices to take your data pipeline game to the next level. No boring theory here - we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking real-world use cases.
Exploring which are the patterns for data pipeline with Airflow+Spark, Airflow+DBT, Airflow+Polars, how to avoid dependencies management on Airflow and resuse DAGs template on our organization.
Define which are the fundamental concepts of a Data Pipeline, from Data Lineage, Data Observability, Metadata, Data quality, Data auditing and how to integrate it on a Data Pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernize APIs to run serverless using Apache CXF</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modernize-apis-to-run-serverless-using-apache-cxf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modernize-apis-to-run-serverless-using-apache-cxf/</guid>
      <description>Years ago the Service-oriented architecture (SOA) architectural style came along with implementations of web services based on standards like the Web Service Description Language (WSDL) and SOAP. Many of these interfaces are still in place as of today as a change requires both provider and all consumers to agree on a new definition and change the implementation (often without any business value). The underlying infrastructure, sometimes based on Enterprise Services Buses (ESB) is however often end-of-life and hard to maintain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving Apache Cassandra command execution and monitoring from JMX to CQL: A Developer&#39;s Overview</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/moving-apache-cassandra-command-execution-and-monitoring-from-jmx-to-cql-a-developer-s-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/moving-apache-cassandra-command-execution-and-monitoring-from-jmx-to-cql-a-developer-s-overview/</guid>
      <description>Monitoring and management go hand in hand in distributed storage systems, and this is true for Apache Cassandra as well. Apache Cassandra has a wide range of monitoring and management API extensions that provide insight into its internal processes and make management operations accessible.
This talk will provide an overview of several new initiatives that are closely related from a software developer&amp;rsquo;s perspective. These initiatives follow the same design principles and their overall direction can be characterized as a strategic shift in both management and monitoring from JMX to CQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi Tenancy — Apache Hbase</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/multi-tenancy-apache-hbase/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/multi-tenancy-apache-hbase/</guid>
      <description>Apache HBase is an open-source non-relational distributed database with multiple components such as Zookeeper, JournalNodes, Hmaster, Namenodes, Datanodes, Regionserver. Managing independent clusters for each use case is operationally heavy and sub-optimal utilization of hardware. Hence there is a need for providing a consolidated, managed, multi-tenant HBase cluster with stronger isolation guarantees in many organizations.
In this talk, we are going to talk about how we approached this problem, made tradeoffs and run large scale multi-tenant hbase clusters with strict isolation guarantees.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Challenges and Enhancing Performance of LLM based Applications</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-challenges-and-enhancing-performance-of-llm-based-applications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-challenges-and-enhancing-performance-of-llm-based-applications/</guid>
      <description>Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) is probably one of the most popular implementations of LLMs that integrates retrieval and generation models, augmenting AI&amp;rsquo;s understanding of text and improving response accuracy through an information database.
This approach tackles the limitations of traditional generation models by fusing retrieval mechanisms, and enriching outputs with contextual depth and external knowledge.
Evaluating applications using LLMs, such as RAG, is pivotal for confidence and improvement, yet faces challenges like subjectiveness with respect to domain-specific suitability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Navigating Podling Releases: Achieving Success in the Apache Incubator</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-podling-releases-achieving-success-in-the-apache-incubator/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/navigating-podling-releases-achieving-success-in-the-apache-incubator/</guid>
      <description>Discover the keys to success when releasing a podling within the Apache Incubator. This talk explores the crucial aspects that the incubator PMC looks for in every release, providing practical tips to pass the IPMC vote and move your project closer to graduation.
Learn about the latest incubator and ASF policies, recent updates you may have missed, and the legal requirements of open source licenses. Gain insights into assembling your NOTICE and LICENSE files effectively, while understanding the reasoning behind specific practices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Obtain, Distribute and Use Temporary Credentials Automatically in Apache Spark and Apache Flink</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/obtain-distribute-and-use-temporary-credentials-automatically-in-apache-spark-and-apache-flink/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/obtain-distribute-and-use-temporary-credentials-automatically-in-apache-spark-and-apache-flink/</guid>
      <description>The importance of security is increasing sharply nowadays which must be reflected in open source projects. Apache Spark and Apache Flink are two of the most widely used Big Data frameworks which can be used for data processing. Both of them offer dozens of external service connectors where authentication plays an essential role. Each external system does its authentication in a different way but a common framework can be provided to ease the life of developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSSL and QUIC using FFM</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/openssl-and-quic-using-ffm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/openssl-and-quic-using-ffm/</guid>
      <description>This session explores the use of the FFM API from Java 22 to leverage native library capabilities, in the context of Apache Tomcat. OpenSSL is here being used to provide support for TLS through the JSSE API, without the need to use the tomcat-native wrapper library. Exploratory design of QUIC and HTTP/3 support from OpenSSL 3.3+ is also discussed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Approaches for Real-Time Machine Learning with Apache Spark on Kubernetes.</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/optimal-approaches-for-real-time-machine-learning-with-apache-spark-on-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/optimal-approaches-for-real-time-machine-learning-with-apache-spark-on-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>As machine learning (ML) models increasingly become integral components of modern applications, there is a growing need to deploy them in real-time environments. Apache Spark is a popular open-source framework for large-scale data processing that supports ML tasks, while Kubernetes provides a powerful platform for container orchestration and deployment. However, combining Spark and Kubernetes poses significant challenges, especially when it comes to achieving low latency and high scalability. In this session, we explore optimal approaches for real-time ML with Apache Spark on Kubernetes, including best practices and strategies for efficient model training, deployment, and serving.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orchestrating Scalable Data Pipelines with Apache Toree, YuniKorn, Spark, and Airflow</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/orchestrating-scalable-data-pipelines-with-apache-toree-yunikorn-spark-and-airflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/orchestrating-scalable-data-pipelines-with-apache-toree-yunikorn-spark-and-airflow/</guid>
      <description>This session explores the integrated use of Apache Toree, YuniKorn, Spark, and Airflow to create efficient, scalable data pipelines. We will start by discussing how Apache Toree provides an interactive analysis environment with Spark via Jupyter Notebook. Then, we’ll discuss using Apache YuniKorn to manage and schedule these computational resources, ensuring system efficiency. Central to our talk, we’ll delve into the role of Apache Spark in large-scale data processing, highlighting its integration with Toree and YuniKorn.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Outreach: The Two-Way Street of Open Source Projects</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/outreach-the-two-way-street-of-open-source-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/outreach-the-two-way-street-of-open-source-projects/</guid>
      <description>There are millions of open source projects people can use and contribute to. Why yours?
Developing an open source project that is valuable to many and widely accepted in an industry requires a lot of care and feeding – and more than just code. Whether your project is brand new or been around for decades, you need to explain why other people should take the time to learn, use, and potentially contribute to it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxia - A Horizontally Scalable Alternative to Apache Zookeeper</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/oxia-a-horizontally-scalable-alternative-to-apache-zookeeper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/oxia-a-horizontally-scalable-alternative-to-apache-zookeeper/</guid>
      <description>For over a decade, Apache Zookeeper has played a crucial role in maintaining configuration information and providing synchronization within distributed systems. Its unique ability to provide these features made it the de facto standard for distributed systems within the Apache community.
Despite its prolific adoption, there is an emerging trend toward eliminating the dependency on Zookeeper altogether and replacing it with an alternative technology. The most notable example is the KRaft subproject within the Apache Kafka community,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pretend it’s a Movie: How to Build Excitement for Your Apache Project</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/pretend-its-a-movie-how-to-build-excitement-for-your-apache-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/pretend-its-a-movie-how-to-build-excitement-for-your-apache-project/</guid>
      <description>How do you explain your Apache project to people who don’t even know how to download apps onto their phones – and still manage to get them excited about what you’re working on? It’s simple: pretend you’re talking about a movie.
The problem isn’t the project, but how we’ve been talking about them. And now we’re going to fix that.
In this talk, discover how to completely change the narrative about discussing Apache and open source by not actually talking about open source or Apache&amp;hellip;but instead using the same principles that marketers use to create excitement around a movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN Options in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/sdn-options-in-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/sdn-options-in-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>Apache CloudStack integrates with two major SDN solutions, Tungsten Fabric (OpenSDN) for KVM environments and NSX for VMWare ESX environments. In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how this integrations were implemented, how to setup ACS Zones with these SDNs and explore their capabilities in regards to ACS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplifying Data Processing with Apache Flink SQL</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/simplifying-data-processing-with-apache-flink-sql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/simplifying-data-processing-with-apache-flink-sql/</guid>
      <description>Apache Flink is a powerful open-source stream processing framework that supports unified batch and streaming processing. With its SQL support, Flink has become even more accessible to data analysts and developers who are familiar with SQL.
In this talk, we will provide a short introduction to Apache Flink and explain how you can leverage SQL under the hood. We will cover some of the SQL-specific features of Flink, such as dynamic tables, streaming SQL and support for stateful operations like windowing and pattern recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solr Eclipse - Zomato&#39;s Journey to 64 Million Search Queries a Day</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/solr-eclipse-zomato-s-journey-to-64-million-search-queries-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/solr-eclipse-zomato-s-journey-to-64-million-search-queries-a-day/</guid>
      <description>Zomato is the Indian market leader for restaurant aggregation and food delivery.
This is a story of how Zomato leverages the power of Apache Solr at scale, some of the problems we faced and how we tackled them to reach where we are now.
Starting with just one Solr instance serving 1000 queries a day with 10K restaurants, to building and shipping a massive, first in class, search server with the capability of seamlessly searching 100 Million restaurant catalogues (SKUs), 800K+ restaurants and 50K+ unique dishes in 13 different languages at 64 Million search queries a day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Apache IoTDB</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/state-of-apache-iotdb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/state-of-apache-iotdb/</guid>
      <description>Apache IoTDB, a time series database focused on IoT workloads. At the end of 2022 the major version 1.0 was released which containted many major changes, e.g. a completely new cluster module, new export and import options and new APIS to integrate with Apache IoTDB.
In 2023 three minor releases, namely 1.1, 1.2 and 1.3 have been released but although they are considered minor releases they contain many new features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of the Civet</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/state-of-the-civet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/state-of-the-civet/</guid>
      <description>An update on what&amp;rsquo;s happened inside the Apache PLC4X over the last year. What we have achieved and what we are planning on doing for the near and not-so-near future.
From new protocols, updated APIs, new languages, GUI applications right up to even more supported languages and fully generated driver implementations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storage Attached Index &amp; Vector Search in Cassandra 5.0</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/storage-attached-index-vector-search-in-cassandra-5-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/storage-attached-index-vector-search-in-cassandra-5-0/</guid>
      <description>This session will be a dive into the internals of SAI and Vector Search in Cassandra 5.0. It will cover the current functionality and limitations of SAI and suggested future priorities for the project. It will also look at the read and write paths for SAI and their relationship to the current Cassandra paths. Finally, it will look at the the in-memory and on-disk data structures used for the indexes and why these were chosen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking with management about open source</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/talking-with-management-about-open-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/talking-with-management-about-open-source/</guid>
      <description>For those of us who already know how important open source is, it can be challenging to persuasively make the case to management, because we assume that everyone already knows the basics. This can work against us, confusing our audience and making us come across as condescending or concerned about irrelevant lofty philosophical points.
In this talk, we take it back to the basics. What does management actually need to know about open source, why it matters, and how to make decisions about consuming open source, contributing to open source, and open sourcing company code?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Accord Consensus Protocol: ACID transactions globally at any scale</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-accord-consensus-protocol-acid-transactions-globally-at-any-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-accord-consensus-protocol-acid-transactions-globally-at-any-scale/</guid>
      <description>The Accord Consensus Protocol, providing global leaderless single-network-round-trip consensus using commodity clocks.
Research from University of Michigan &amp;amp; Apple Inc. introduces ACID-compliant, strict serialisable transactions that can run globally at scale, at high throughput, with low latency.
This will be a run-through of
the importance of ACID transactions in Apache Cassandra,
how previous consensus protocols work,
how Accord improves on these to provide its industry leading characteristics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The right feature at the right place: the example of authorization</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-right-feature-at-the-right-place-the-example-of-authorization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-right-feature-at-the-right-place-the-example-of-authorization/</guid>
      <description>All mature tech stacks nowadays offer infrastructure-related capabilities, either a standard lib or in 3rd-party libraries, e.g., rate-limiting and authorization. While it&amp;rsquo;s great to have such features, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to audit them easily. You&amp;rsquo;d need to be familiar with the stack and dive deep into the code. This approach just doesn&amp;rsquo;t scale,
A well-designed system keeps the right feature at the right place. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll go through all steps toward making your system more easily auditable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unified Compaction Strategy in Cassandra 5</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-unified-compaction-strategy-in-cassandra-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/the-unified-compaction-strategy-in-cassandra-5/</guid>
      <description>Choosing a compaction strategy for a Cassandra database has historically been a very difficult problem, where making the wrong choice can have lasting effects on performance while making a change later is a time-consuming and costly process.
The Unified Compaction Strategy, introduced with Cassandra 5, is designed to provide a solution to this problem by effectively handling a diverse range of use cases, including those best suited for leveled, tiered, and time-windowed compaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Impala not only reads, but modifies and optimizes Iceberg tables</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/this-impala-not-only-reads-but-modifies-and-optimizes-iceberg-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/this-impala-not-only-reads-but-modifies-and-optimizes-iceberg-tables/</guid>
      <description>Apache Impala is a distributed, massively parallel query engine for big data. Initially, it focused on fast query execution on top of large datasets that were ingested via long-running batch jobs. The table schema and the ingested data typically remained unchanged, and row-level modifications were impractical to say the least.
Today&amp;rsquo;s expectations for modern data warehouse engines have risen significantly. Users now want to have RDBMS-like capabilities in their data warehouses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomcat 11 and Jakarta EE 11</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/tomcat-11-and-jakarta-ee-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/tomcat-11-and-jakarta-ee-11/</guid>
      <description>Apache Tomcat implements the Jakarta Servlet, Jakarta Pages, Jakarta Expression Language, Jakarta WebSocket and Jakarta Authentication specifications. Jakarta EE 11 is due for release in the first half of 2024 with the first stable Tomcat 11 release expected shortly afterwards.
This session will look at the changes in Jakarta EE 11 for the specifications that Tomcat implements and what these changes mean for developers looking to deploying their application on Tomcat 11.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from VMware to Apache CloudStack: A Path to Profitability and Competitiveness</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/transitioning-from-vmware-to-apache-cloudstack-a-path-to-profitability-and-competitiveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/transitioning-from-vmware-to-apache-cloudstack-a-path-to-profitability-and-competitiveness/</guid>
      <description>In this session, we will explore the potential of migrating from VMware to Apache CloudStack with KVM. VMware vSphere is a robust cloud infrastructure and management solution that combines vSphere and vRealize Suite, providing automation and operations capabilities for traditional and modern infrastructure and apps. However, the transition to Apache CloudStack can offer enhanced profitability and competitiveness.
We will delve into the benefits of Apache CloudStack, including its cost-effectiveness and open-source nature, and discuss how a gradual migration from VMware vCloud can reduce ownership costs, increase profitability, and enhance competitiveness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding stream table duality using Kafka, Flink SQL and Debezium format</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/understanding-stream-table-duality-using-kafka-flink-sql-and-debezium-format/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/understanding-stream-table-duality-using-kafka-flink-sql-and-debezium-format/</guid>
      <description>Kafka Streams, ksqlDB or Flink SQL are popular processing engines that enable us to run SQL queries on top of streaming data. Isn&amp;rsquo;t it fascinating that we can run SQL queries on top of streaming data as if they were relational tables, or convert a table into a stream of changelog events? This is known as the stream-table duality.
In this talk we will try to understand how it works under the hood using Flink SQL, Kafka connector with Debezium JSON/Avro format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleash the power of Asynchronous Decision Making</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleash-the-power-of-asynchronous-decision-making/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleash-the-power-of-asynchronous-decision-making/</guid>
      <description>The Asynchronous Decision Making techniques commonly used in open source projects enable efficient remote collaboration, in teams which have no boss, no schedule and often no cultural consistency yet produce world-changing software.
These very efficient collaboration techniques can even work without computers and apply to most types of projects, not just software development.
This talk describes the key elements and tools of the Asynchronous Decision Making process, based on more than twenty five years of experience in Open Source projects, as well as examples from federated governments, which, interestingly, work in a similar way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing High Concurrency Real-Time IoT Queries with Apache Druid</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleashing-high-concurrency-real-time-iot-queries-with-apache-druid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unleashing-high-concurrency-real-time-iot-queries-with-apache-druid/</guid>
      <description>Apache Druid is a real-time analytics database built for speed and scale, capable of executing complex queries against billions of rows and getting sub-second answers. Druid thrives on highly concurrent workloads, making it ideal for applications like website clickstream analysis, network performance monitoring, or handling vast IoT metrics. By using pre-aggregated data, lightning-fast columnar storage, and parallel processing we can gain insights in real-time.
In this talk, we will share techniques for improving query concurrency and achieving sub-second responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking Insights: Data Federation</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unlocking-insights-data-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/unlocking-insights-data-federation/</guid>
      <description>With great data comes great responsibilities! Companies of every scale face issues of managing huge amounts of data spread across various platforms, databases, and applications.
Data federation offers a solution to this problem by integrating and accessing data from various data sources without the need for complex ETL processes or data duplication.
This session will delve into the following key aspects of data federation:
Introduction to Data Federation:
The problem today?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vector Search at Uber</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vector-search-at-uber/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vector-search-at-uber/</guid>
      <description>Vector Search has been regarded as a revolution for Search and Information Retrieval since the breakthrough with BERT and GPT in 2018. There has been an ever growing interest from both academia and industry in using machine learning models and vector search to leverage all sorts of content beyond the lexical features, including images, events, contextual semantics and so on.
At Uber, we added the Vector Search support by leveraging Apache Lucene to our Search platform, and empower multiple business-critical use cases, such as Semantic Search and Gen AI support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNF Integration and Support in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vnf-integration-and-support-in-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vnf-integration-and-support-in-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>In this session Wei will present how CloudStack 4.19 adds the capability to easily and quickly perform a light-touch integration of networking appliances with Apache CloudStack, allowing for operators and end users to offer a broader range of networking services while empowering end-users to effortlessly deploy their own virtualized network functions (VNFs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebAssembly plugin for Apache Traffic Server</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/webassembly-plugin-for-apache-traffic-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/webassembly-plugin-for-apache-traffic-server/</guid>
      <description>The WebAssembly (Wasm) plugin for Apache Traffic Server (ATS) allows WebAssembly modules following the &amp;ldquo;proxy-wasm&amp;rdquo; specification to be run on ATS.
The talk will begin by first introducing the background and history of plugins and programmability of ATS. I will go over the short comings of the current offerings and then introduce the Wasm plugin as an alternative solution for them. I will then talk about the &amp;ldquo;proxy-wasm&amp;rdquo; specification, which describes the support of WebAssembly modules for proxy server software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whisky Clustering with Apache Projects: Groovy, Commons Math, Ignite, Spark, Wayang and Beam</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whisky-clustering-with-apache-projects-groovy-commons-math-ignite-spark-wayang-and-beam/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whisky-clustering-with-apache-projects-groovy-commons-math-ignite-spark-wayang-and-beam/</guid>
      <description>Calling all developers with a penchant for fine whiskey! Join Dr. Paul King, VP at Apache Groovy, on a quest to analyze whiskeys produced by the world’s top 86 distilleries to identify the perfect single-malt Scotch.
How will he perform this analysis? By using the traditional and distributed K-means clustering algorithm from various Apache projects. Bottoms up!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitefox: simple table format sharing</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the evolving landscape of data platforms, the decoupling of compute and storage has led to the emergence of open data systems free from vendor constraints. However, this shift towards &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;modularity&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; brings its own set of challenges. The intricate task of establishing effective access controls within table-format architectures proves to be complex. Despite data residing in the cloud and theoretically accessible from anywhere, the existing friction impedes seamless accessibility.
Enter Whitefox: an open-source initiative inspired by the brilliant principles of Delta-Sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Apache Kafka Clusters Are Like Galaxies (And Other Cosmic Kafka Quandaries Explored)</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-apache-kafka-clusters-are-like-galaxies-and-other-cosmic-kafka-quandaries-explored/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-apache-kafka-clusters-are-like-galaxies-and-other-cosmic-kafka-quandaries-explored/</guid>
      <description>Instaclustr (now part of NetApp) manages 100s of Apache Kafka clusters of many different sizes, for a variety of use cases and customers. For the last 7 years I’ve been focused outwardly on exploring Kafka application development challenges, but recently I decided to look inward and see what I could discover about the performance, scalability and resource characteristics of the Kafka clusters themselves. Using a suite of Performance Engineering techniques, I will reveal some surprising discoveries about cosmic Kafka mysteries in our data centres, related to: cluster sizes and distribution (using Zipf’s Law), horizontal vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why is it So Hard...</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-is-it-so-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/why-is-it-so-hard/</guid>
      <description>to submit patches to a podling?
to release code to the public?
to maintain trademarks for a podling?
to become a committer on a podling?
This talk explains what common barriers are to accomplishing objectives of people and projects. It explains why The ASF has:
licensing requirements for code submissions and releases,
signing and checksums, download protocols,
voting requirements for releases and project membership,
trademark requirements for web sites and documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
