<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Riccardo Amadio on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/riccardo-amadio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Riccardo Amadio on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/speakers/riccardo-amadio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modern Data Orchestrators</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modern-data-orchestrators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/modern-data-orchestrators/</guid>
      <description>In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through the tricks and best practices to take your data pipeline game to the next level. No boring theory here - we&amp;rsquo;ll be talking real-world use cases.
Exploring which are the patterns for data pipeline with Airflow+Spark, Airflow+DBT, Airflow+Polars, how to avoid dependencies management on Airflow and resuse DAGs template on our organization.
Define which are the fundamental concepts of a Data Pipeline, from Data Lineage, Data Observability, Metadata, Data quality, Data auditing and how to integrate it on a Data Pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whitefox: simple table format sharing</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/whitefox-simple-table-format-sharing/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In the evolving landscape of data platforms, the decoupling of compute and storage has led to the emergence of open data systems free from vendor constraints. However, this shift towards &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;modularity&amp;rdquo;&amp;rdquo; brings its own set of challenges. The intricate task of establishing effective access controls within table-format architectures proves to be complex. Despite data residing in the cloud and theoretically accessible from anywhere, the existing friction impedes seamless accessibility.
Enter Whitefox: an open-source initiative inspired by the brilliant principles of Delta-Sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
