<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CloudStack on Community Over Code Europe</title>
    <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/tracks/cloudstack/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CloudStack on Community Over Code Europe</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language><atom:link href="https://eu.communityovercode.org/tracks/cloudstack/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Incremental snapshots/backups in KVM plugin of Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/incremental-snapshots-backups-in-kvm-plugin-of-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/incremental-snapshots-backups-in-kvm-plugin-of-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>Apache CloudStack (ACS) and KVM are a combination that many organizations decided to adopt. KVM is a widely used hypervisor with a vibrant community and support in different operating system distributions. While developing the KVM plugin functionalities, one normally tries to make use of the full potential of the hypervisor; however, while Libvirt, the toolkit used by ACS to manage KVM VMs, already supports native incremental snapshots, every volume snapshot/backup taken with ACS is a full snapshot/backup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SDN Options in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/sdn-options-in-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/sdn-options-in-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>Apache CloudStack integrates with two major SDN solutions, Tungsten Fabric (OpenSDN) for KVM environments and NSX for VMWare ESX environments. In this talk we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how this integrations were implemented, how to setup ACS Zones with these SDNs and explore their capabilities in regards to ACS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VNF Integration and Support in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vnf-integration-and-support-in-apache-cloudstack/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://eu.communityovercode.org/sessions/2024/vnf-integration-and-support-in-apache-cloudstack/</guid>
      <description>In this session Wei will present how CloudStack 4.19 adds the capability to easily and quickly perform a light-touch integration of networking appliances with Apache CloudStack, allowing for operators and end users to offer a broader range of networking services while empowering end-users to effortlessly deploy their own virtualized network functions (VNFs).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
